星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯 前情提要
Previously on Stargate Atlantis
它正冲城市飞去!
It's headed for the city !
- 它在干什么?
- 扫描我们 ..
- What's it doing ?
- Scanning us ..
那艘飞船已经向宇宙深处
传送了一些信号
Now the dart sent a transmission deep into space,
然后在我们可以靠近的时候自毁了
and then it self destructed before we could get to it.
- 已经用我们的深空探测器扫描了那片区域..
- 那些是什么?
- We scanned the area with our deep-space sensors and..
- What are those ?
幽灵的母船 一共有三艘
Wraith hives ship. Three of them.
它们飞向哪里?
Where are they headed ?
如果保持现在的方向和速度
三周后它们将会到达我们的星球
If they maintain direction and speed,
they'll be over our planet within two weeks.
我们已经知道他们要来了
至少现在知道了它们何时会来
We knew they were comming,
at least now we know when.
- 一定有办法
- 有办法?
- That's something.
- That's something ?
我们还有时间, Rodney.
现在没有理由恐慌
There's still time, Rodney.
There's no reason to panic...
只要还有时间, 就一定会有希望
- yet.
- Where there is time, there is hope.
同意 有什么建议?
Agreed. So recommandations ?
- 除了恐慌之外?
- 除了恐慌, 是的!
- Other than panic ?
- Other than panic, yes!
我知道这可能不是很好
不过我们可以考虑 M7G-677...
I realize this might not be cool,
but we should consider M7G-677.
- 作为一个可能的疏散点?
- 不, 女士
- As a possible evacuation site ?
- No ma'am.
我建议我们取走他们的ZPM
I'm suggesting we take their ZPM.
他们唯一防护幽灵的途径?
Their only means of protection from the Wraith ?
一个大部分由孩子居住的星球
A planet populated mostly by children.
他的观点是有根据的
我们已经确定了那个ZPM已经快枯竭了
不过对我们可能还有些用
He raises a valid point. We've already
established the ZPM is nearly depleted,
but it could be of some limited use to us.
你刚才让我们提建议
这是我们生存下来的一种方法
You asked for suggestions. It's a matter of survival.
我知道了
I see.
我们还没有走到那一步
只要我还在掌管这里, 我们永远也不会去那里
We're not quite there yet.
And as long as I'm in charge, we will never be there.
我同意Weir博士的观点
I agree doctor Weir.
即便这就是我们的结局
我们也应该体面的应对它
If this is to be our end, it is best
we face it with both dignity and honor.
- 实际上我有一个想法, 除了恐慌之外
- 说出来听听
- To that end I actually have an idea, in addition, to panic.
- Let's hear it.
虽然比较繁琐, 不过我想还是值得的
当然, 大部分要归功于我的...
It's really a long shot, but I think it's most likely
worth the effort, of course the most to be my efforts...
到底是什么?
What is it ?
我想我们可以通过星际之门
给地球发回一条消息
I think we can send a message
back to Earth through the Stargate.
- 抱歉?
- 我想我们没有足够的能量
- Excuse me ?
- I thought we didn't have enough power.
对于传送一个人来说, 确实不够
我们没有办法让虫洞维持足够长的时间
Not to send a person, no. We'd never be
able to maintain the wormhole long enough.
不过我想如果我们把所有可以用的
能源集中到一起
But I think if we would be able to tie together
all of our power generating capabilities,
我们可能, 我强调的一下, 是可能
建立一个足够久的虫洞并发送一条消息
we might - and I emphasise might - be able to establish
a wormhole long enough to send a message.
大概是多长时间?
How much time are we talking about ?
大约, 1.3 秒, 发送或者接收
Aproximatly, 1.3 seconds, give or take.
- 这时间不够
- 只够喊SOS了
- That's not much time.
- Time enough to say S.O.S.
不是用模拟方式
如果需要发送的消息是经过了高度压缩的
1.3秒完全足够了
Don't be so analogue. 1.3 seconds is
more than enough time to send the message
if it's in the form of a high compression data burst.
几年前, 我曾经帮助美国空军
优化过编码算法
Now, I helped refine the encoding
for the US Air Force a few years back.
- Carter上校在那边应该知道如何解密
- 你建议我们现在就开始干?
- Colonel Carter should be able to decipher it on the other side.
- You're suggesting this now ?
因为它可能不会成功, 而且很有可能
在进行当中会让我们的发电机过载
Because it probably won't work, and there's
a very good chance it could overload
our naquadah generators in the process.
好啊, 那我们就不应该去冒这个险!
Well then we can't take the risk !
没有能量, 我们就没有任何机会了
No power, we won't have a chance in hell.
有三艘幽灵的母船正朝这里飞来, 少校
非常时候就应该采取非常措施
There are three Wraith hives ship on the way, Major.
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
除此之外, 我过去几天一直在想办法
尽量让失败的可能性降到最低
Besides, I spent the last few days
working of ways of minimizing the risk.
假如这是可能的, 我们可以发送多少信息?
Assuming it's possible, how much information can we send ?
任何东西 亚特兰蒂斯所有资深组员的
任务报告, 所有我们在飞马座学到的东西
Everything. I mean, mission reports from all
the senior staff, a ton of stuff on Atlantis,
things we've learned in Pegasus.
- 所有的? 一秒钟?
- 一点三秒
- All that ? One second ?
- One point three.
我还可以更加优化压缩比率
你们会找着东西来加进去的
You jest, but if I could finesse the compression
ratios, you'll be looking for things to add.
- 做吧
- 就开始
- Do it.
- Doing it.
Elizabeth, 你应该知道
如果星际之门的指挥官能够发出求救信号...
Elizabeth, you realize that if
Stargate Command was able to send help..
我知道 不过我们仍然有责任报告
我们在这里学习到的东西
I know. They would have. But still we've the
responsability to report what we've learned here.
- 关于亚特兰蒂斯, 关于古人...
- 幽灵?
- About Atlantis, about the Ancients..
- The Wraith ?
是的, 我们必须提醒地球
Exactly. We have to warn Earth.
即使这是我们所做的最后一件事?
Even if it's the last thing we do ?
如果是最后一件事, 那就尤其如此
Especially if it's the last thing we do.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第17集 飞马座来信
Season 1 : Episode 17
Letters from Pegasus
那些屏幕上的小点,
它们看起来并不危险, 是不是?
They don't seem threatening,
those dots on the screen, do they?
这就是为什么我们要去实地侦察
去获取第一手的资料
Which is why we need to do recon and
see what we're up against firsthand.
怎样去?
How ?
我已经跟踪了它们的行进路线
幽灵的飞船很显然会周期性的进出超空间
I've been tracking their progress. The Wraith ships
apparently go in and out of hyperspace periodically.
- 要么是它们关于超空间的技术十分有限....
- 要么是它们在沿路洗劫
- Either because their hyperspace technology is limited....
- Or they're stopping to feed along the way.
重要的是, 这种行进模式是可以预测的
The point is, the pattern is predictable.
我可以断定, 它们会在
这里,  这里和这里停一下
I can guess with some certainty, that
they'll be making stops, here, here and here.
即便是这样, 这些飞船仍然在数光年以外
我们如何让我们的小飞船去接近它们?
Even so, those ships are light years away. How
do you expect to reach them in a puddle jumper?
我们可以飞到一个途中的星际之门
Zelenka认为它们会在那里脱离超空间
然后就在旁边观察它们
We fly to a Stargate en route that Zelenka thinks they're
gonna drop out of hyperspace, and we watch them pass by.
- 不错
- 你知道我已经准备好了
- That's good.
- You know I have my moments.
我和Teyla刚才已经决定了将去哪个星球
Teyla and I were just deciding which planet to go to.
我跟这个星球上的人们很熟
I am familiar with the people of this world.
他们的星际之门处于开放状态
可以通过一艘飞船
Their Stargate is in the open,
and so, accessible by ship.
你确信在幽灵经过你们的时候
不会被发现?
And you think you can remain undetected
by the Wraith as they go by your position?
隐形模式
它们甚至不知道我们在那里
Stealth mode. They won't even know we're there.
好吧, 去吧, 尽可能多的获取信息
记得在Rodney发送消息前回来
我要你们两个都回到这里
OK, go. Get what intel you can and get back before
Rodney sends his message. I need the both of you here.
在任务完成前, 我们是不会停下的
Won't even stop at the duty free.
千万不要试图去和幽灵的飞船交火
我在这里命令你, 不要这样做
On the offchance that you get the idea to take the Wraith
ships on yourself Major. I am hereby ordering you not to.
相信我, 不会的
Believe me you don't have to.
再强调一次
Still.
"不要只身赤手空拳与敌舰搏斗"
我明白
"Don't take on alien armada's single handedly."
I understand.
父亲! Teyla来了!
Father! Teyla's here!
Teyla!
- Oren! 好久不见了
- 很久了, 瞧你, 变了许多
- Oren! It has been many days.
- Too many. Look at you, you're so different.
自从我上次拜访之后
很多东西都发生了改变
Much has changed since my last visit.
- 这位是John Sheppard少校. 这是Oren
- 很高兴见到你
- This is Major John Sheppard. And Oren.
- Pleased to meet you.
- 现在离收获还有好几个月
- 是的, 我知道
- The harvest is still months away.
- Yes, I know.
我们到这里来不是为了交易
我们是来提醒你们
We have not come to trade, but to deliver a warning.
我们有理由相信幽灵已经在路上
We have reason to believe
the Wraith may be on their way.
我们无法确信
不过我们就要去搞清楚
We don't know that for a fact,
but we're about to go and find out.
是的, 看起来它们正在到处醒来
Yes, it seems they're awakening everywhere.
你应该告诉你的人民
做好防范它们到来的措施
You should tell your people
to take precautions in case they do come.
我会的
I will.
不过你也知道, Teyla, 无论你去哪里
它们都有办法找到. 逃不掉的
But you know as well as I do Teyla, that the Wraith will
track us down wherever we go. There will be no escape.
那么通过星际之门呢?
What about through the Stargate?
洗劫会在很多个星球上发生
没有地方是安全的
The cullings are taking place
on many worlds. None are safe.
即便是我们找到了避难所
Even we have taken in refugees.
如果他们真的来了, 尽量离星际之门远点
带你的家人到树林的边缘, 那里, 等着我们
If they do come, stay far from the Stargate. Take
your family to the far treeline, there, and wait for us.
- Teyla.
- 一个家庭, 少校, 这就是我的全部要求
- One family Major, that is all I ask.
我很抱歉Oren, 我不能保证
I'm sorry Oren, I can't make that promise.
至少, 这是我们可以做到的
It will be the very least we can do.
- 如果有时间的话
- 那我们就必须赶紧
- If there's time.
- Then we must hurry.
孩子们, 我们必须做好准备
Children, we must prepare.
好了, 我们已经准备好了城市的布局图,
任务报告以及作战评估
Alright, we have our city' specs, mission reports
and tactical assessments all ready to go.
还有什么?
What else ?
我已经附上了一大堆我们所能够解密的
来自古人数据库的数据
Well I've included a ton of data that we've been
able to decipher from the Ancient database.
真的么? 难以置信
Really? That is incredible.
我所设计的压缩算法非常有效
Well the algorithm I've devised
is extraordinarily efficient, yes.
哦, 求你了!
Oh please!
必须是这样
否则没办法在1.3秒内发完所有的数据
Well it must be,
in order to fit all that data into 1.3 seconds.
事实上, 只用去了0.3 秒
.3 seconds actually.
我们还有整整一秒钟来发送数据?
We have a whole extra second to fill?
整整一秒钟, 是这样
A whole extra one, yes.
足够用来发送个人消息么?
Is it enough to include personal messages?
当然, 可以包括几小时的视频
如果我们限制音频的话, 还可以更多
Sure, I mean several hours of video.
Much more if we restrict the audio.
我想我们在精神上非常需要这个
特别是现在
I think it'll do wonders for moral. Especially now.
我可以告诉我们的奶奶
我这些时候都做了些什么
I could tell my Grandma
what I've been up to all this time.
当然, 如果你的奶奶有足够的安全许可的话
是的, 你可以
Well if your grandmother had security clearance,
yes you could.
不过目前, 你可以告诉她
你很好, 而且你很想念她
But for now, you can tell her
that you're well and that you miss her.
这些都非常吸引人, 不过,
我还有工作要去做. 我是不是...
This is all very charming, but um,
I have work to do. Shouldn't I...
中尉, 也许你可以来处理一下
Lieutenant, maybe you'd like to handle this.
给每个人在镜头前几分钟的机会
让他们可以给所爱的人发一条个人消息
Give everybody a few minutes on camera send
a personal message to their loved ones.
我很乐意
I'd love to ma'am.
好了去做吧!
Off you go!
只要我和Zelenka 把四号飞船的引擎
成功接入到能源网
As soon as Zelenka and I can get
Jumper 4's engines tied into the grid,
我们就可以进行低能量演练了
we should be able to do a low power dry run.
很好
Good.
Rodney?
你不想给什么人发条消息么?
You don't want to send a message to anyone?
你知道么? 我想我会利用所有的空余时间,
为我自己录制一条消息
You know what? I think with all my spare time,
I'll just record a message to myself.
你认为呢?
You?
当然
Yes.
好的, 好的
Good, good.
这并不是一个拯救行动
This wasn't supposed to be a rescue mission.
Oren是我父亲的好朋友
Oren was a good friend of my father.
我想提醒你
I agreed to warn him.
如果有人跟你的家人很亲近
If someone close to your family,
一个亲近的朋友, 正处于将被幽灵带走的危险之中
你能够无动于衷么?
a dear friend, was in danger of being taken by
the Wraith, would you have not done the same?
如果这危及这次任务, 我会的
Not if it jeopardised the mission.
这么说与幽灵斗争, 我们就要舍弃
我们同它们的不同之处么?
So in fighting the Wraith, we are to give up
that which makes us different from them?
我同意停下来把他带上, 如果有时间的话
但如果没有时间, 我也无能为力
I agreed to stop and pick him up
if there was time, but only if there was time.
如我们可以, 我愿意拯救这个星系中的所有人
I'll be saving everyone
in the damn galaxy, if we could.
一个人连同他的孩子不是所有人
One man and his children are not every person.
我同意提供帮助, 如果有时间的话
I agreed to help, if there was time.
我们必须量力而行
You only fight the battles you can win.
我们转过去看看
Let's get this thing turn around.
它们正朝那个星球而去
They're heading for the planet.
OK, 开始录了, 电池很足
OK, recording, plenty of battery.
为什么我什么也没有看到
So why am I not seeing anything.
真蠢!
Stupid!
OK. 嗨, 爷爷, 奶奶!
OK. Hi Grandma, Grandpa!
是我Aiden, 当然
It's me Aiden, obviously.
来自一个离家很远, 很远的地方
Talking to you from a place, far, far, from home.
我很好, 你们不用担心
I'm good though. You don't have to worry.
这里的生活很平常
Life here is pretty routine.
我希望不久后就可以回家
不过你们知道, 如果
I'm hoping to get home sometime soon.
But you know, if
我不得不在这里多呆一会儿
我希望你们知道我很好
I'm stuck here a while,
I want you to know that I'm good.
我正在做一些我从来没有想到的事情
I'm doing things, seeing things
I never thought I'd see.
真希望能告诉你们一切
谁知道呢, 也许某一天, 我就可以跟你们说了
Wish I could tell you all about it.
Who knows, one day, maybe I'll be able to.
不过我希望你们知道
But I want you both to know,
你们就在这里, 永远, 任何时候
that you're right here, always, all the time.
抱歉Teyla. 即使以最快速度飞行
我们也只是刚刚比它们的舰队提前一点
Sorry Teyla. Even flying full out,
we're just ahead of the armada.
我不能冒险下去接Oren和他的家人
I can't risk putting down for Oren or his family.
知道了
I see.
我准备让我们脱离隐形状态, 以穿过星际之门
拨号吧
I'm gonna take us out of stealth mode for the pass.
Dial the gate.
等一下! 有虫洞连接进来!
Hang on! Incoming wormhole!
我听过一些故事
幽灵会拨号进来
I have heard stories of the Wraith dialling in,
以阻止受害人
通过星际之门逃跑
to prevent their victims from
using the Stargate as a means of escape.
这么说我们滞留在这里了
So we're stuck here.
只要让这艘飞船再次处于隐形状态
我们就会非常安全
Once the ship is rendered invisible again,
we will be perfectly safe.
我更担心的是, 不久以后
幽灵的舰队就会抵达亚特兰蒂斯
I'm more worried about getting the intel
about the Wraith fleet back to Atlantis.
我们至少可以整个晚上
不断的拨号
Then we'll keep dialling in through
the night at the very least.
不过如果我们等在
我告诉Oren 和他家人的那个地方...
But if we wait in the location
I told Oren and his family to meet us...
我正在赶往那里
That's where I'm headed.
我必须提醒你
我并不是很擅长做这种事情
I must warn you,
I'm not very good at this sort of thing.
不用担心
这个只有你和你的家人才会看到
Well don't worry. The only people
that's gonna see it, is you and your family.
是的, 还有你和美国军方
Aye, and you and the US military.
准备好了么?
Give it a shot?
我应该说什么?
What shall I say?
我想念你? 我希望你也在这里?
I miss you? I wish you were here?
我希望谁在这里?
I wish who was here?
我不知道. 你希望谁在这里?
I don't know. Who do you wish was here?
没有谁! 我只希望我不在这里!
Nobody! I wish I wasn't bloody here!
博士, 我还有很多人要去拍呢
Doc, I got a lotta people I gotta get through.
好吧, 嗯, 我想
我可以向我的母亲问好
Alright, uh, I suppose
I could say hello to my Mother.
很好, 就这样. 好了, 准备好了么?
Good. There you go. Alright, you ready?
是的
Yeah.
OK, 说吧
OK, go.
Hello, 妈妈!
我希望看到这个消息的时候你还好
Hello Mum! I hope this message finds you well.
我相信你的牵牛花现在正在盛开
I trust your petunia's are in full bloom by now.
噢, 我真希望
你还在用我给你的那些药膏
Oh, and I do hope you're keeping up
with the ointment I gave you.
如果你坚持治疗
那些真菌感染现在应该完全好了
If you've adhered to the regime,
the fungus should have cleared up by now.
- 有什么不对么?
- 什么, 真菌?
- What's wrong?
- Dude, fungus?
在她的脚指甲上  你刚才不是说过,
除了我的家人没人会看到的么?
On her toenails. I thought you said no-one
would watch this except my family?
是的, 不过真菌?
Yeah, but fungus?
那我到底应该说些什么?
What then shall I talk about?
我不知道, 她是你母亲
跟她说你爱她
I don't know, it's your Mother.
Tell her you love her.
不, 不, 我不能这样做
我在感情上承受不了
No, no, I can't do that. I'll get all emotional.
是么?
So?
我的妈妈, 她非常的敏感
就像你碰到的最美好的灵魂
She's very delicate, my mother.
As sweet a soul as you'll ever meet.
跟刚刚飘落的雪花一样纯洁 如果我很不安
那么她也会不安, 所以我不能这样做
As pure as the driven snow. If I get upset
then she'll get upset, and I can't have that.
我们并不是在现场直播, 博士
It's not like we're live Doc.
如果你不喜欢我们录在带子上的东西
我们可以再来一次
I mean, you don't like what we put on tape
the first time,we can always do it again.
- 可以么?
- 当然
- We can?
- Sure.
噢  那么我想我可以了
Oh. I suppose I could do that then.
好吧, 我们开始吧
Alright, here we go.
妈妈...
Mum...
我真是太想你了
I miss you terribly.
我做不到!
I can't do this!
来啊Oren, 快点出现!
Come on Oren, show up!
怎么了?
What?
就在不久前, 你还非常乐意他们丢下
Not long ago you would have blithely left them behind.
好吧, 现在情况不同了
Well the situation has changed.
今天早些时候, Ford中尉建议
我们去偷一群孩子
Earlier today Lt Ford suggested
we steal from a community of children.
那是因为他们有ZPM
我们可以把他们一齐带回来
That's because they have a ZPM
and we can bring them back.
到亚特兰蒂斯来等死?
Only to face death in Atlantis?
我和Ford都是军人
我们牺牲了无数条生命来学会如何生存
Look, Ford and I are military. We've spent
a lot of our lives learning how to survive.
我整个一生都在学习
如何在幽灵的威胁下生存
I've spent my life surviving the Wraith.
训练的一部分就是要明白
哪些人你可以救, 哪些你不能
Part of that training is knowing who
you can save and who you can't.
然后决定就是你们自己?
And that decision is yours alone?
我说过如果有时间, 我会等你的朋友
I said that I'd wait for your friend if there was time.
现在就有时间
你还想要我做什么?
Now there's time. What else do you want from me?
我实在是太害怕了
Too much I fear.
这将会是一个漫长的夜晚
It's gonna be a long night.
你并没有说那需要安全许可 是不是?
You didn't say anything that would
require security clearance did you?
安全许可?
Security clearance?
只能在这里坐视不管, 实在是受不了
This is hard, to sit and watch.
我们什么也做不了
There's nothing you can do.
我们可以做很多事
We can do a lot.
不过那将会是我们所做的最后一件事
It'll just be the last thing we ever do.
我们试了很多次了
星际之门仍然无法拨通
We are far outnumbered and
the Gate is still inaccessible.
不过如果我们救了Oren 和他的家人
我们也算是做了一些事情
But if we save Oren and his family,
we will have done something.
某些事
Something.
我会想你的kiddo
I'm gonna miss you kiddo.
我等不住想马上回到家里
带你去看篮球比赛
I can't wait to get back home and
take you to a basketball game.
看着科比和奥尼尔
为湖人再赢得一次冠军
Watch Kobe and Shaq take
another title home for the Lakers.
就这
That's it.
就这?
That's it?
我还可以对孩子说些什么
What else am I gonna say to the kid.
是你的小弟弟SGT?
It's your little brother SGT.
我可能再也见不着他了
为什么要让事情变得更糟呢
And I'm probably never gonna see him again,
why make it worse than it has to be.
- 那跟这个无关!
- 那就是这样做的目的
- That's not what this is about man!
- That's exactly what this is about.
别担心, 中尉
Don't sweat it Lt.
我很高兴我有机会说再见
I'm happy I got the chance to say goodbye.
是的, 不过你并没有说
Yeah, but you didn't say it.
要说的话太多
Not in so many words.
Ford中尉!
Lt Ford!
啊, 你准备好录制你的消息了?
Ah, you ready to record your message?
差不多已经完了
Already done.
实际上我利用特权私下为自己录好了
Actually I took the liberty of doing mine in private.
可能需要一些编辑
Now it may require some editing.
编辑
Editing.
是的, 我讲的可能有点多了
事实上我录了一整盘带子.
Yeah, I went on a bit.
Actually I used the entire tape.
你讲了一个小时?
You talked for an hour.
事实上, 我发现这很有治疗作用
See, I found it rather therapeutic actually.
我很自信, 我提出了一些很有价值的观点
事实上, 我非常确信
Now I'm fairly confident I've come up
with several valuable insights. In fact I'm sure of it,
不过最近几天我只睡了六个小时
but I've only slept six hours in the last few days.
这是给谁的?
Who's it for?
总体来说, 是给我妹妹的
Humanity in general, my sister. Look,
我不想你把它剪成几分钟
我的意思是, 这里面的东西跟金子一样重要
I don't expect you to cut it down to just a few minutes.
I mean, there is gold in here.
把我的放在最后面. 这样, 如果被剪掉,
没事, 只要星际之门的连接可以多维持几毫秒
我们就不会浪费那段时间
So just make sure mine's last and that way, if it gets
cut off, fine, but if the gate holds the connection a few extra
milliseconds then we won't have wasted the time.
我也很期盼这样
I look forward to it.
好吧, 好好欣赏吧
Well, enjoy.
金子
Gold.
预备, 5,4,3....
And in, 5,4,3....
正在同你说话的是Rodney McKay博士
现在是在失落的城市亚特兰蒂斯
我的操作实验室内
This is Doctor Rodney McKay speaking to you
from my base of operations in the lost city of Atlantis,
位于飞马星系的深处
located deep within the Pegasus Galaxy.
我在我们黑暗的时刻来临之前
录下来这些信息
I record this message on the eve of our darkest hour.
在我讲话的同时
一个外星舰队正朝我们开来
As I speak, an alien armada of biblical proportions
is on it's way, bent, dare I say hellbent,
准备将我们毁灭
in keeping with the metaphor, on our destruction.
我们将尽可能的延缓它们的进攻
不过我不得不说战败是不可避免的
We will do our best to stave off their attack,
but I'm afraid that defeat is all but inevitable.
我, 以及探险队中的其他人
I and the other members of my team,
面对的是无法想象的恐怖的死亡
face the most horrific deaths imaginable.
我们的生命将会以一种恐怖的方式
从胸部被吸食...
As our very lives are sucked
from our chests in a horrific....
OK, OK. 从头再来, 从头再来
OK, OK. Starting again. Starting again.
Ford, 把刚才那段剪掉了么?
Ford, just cut that alright?
那是什么?
What is that?
我从没有见过这种东西
I've never seen such a thing.
我要去仔细看看
I'm gonna check it out.
你会被发现的
You may be discovered.
- 我会想办法不被发现
- 少校
- I'll make a point not to.
- Major
我只是想看看那到底是什么
I just want to see whatever that is.
等在这里, 直到Oren和他的家人出现
Just stay here until Oren and his family show up.
倒计时 5, 4,3...
In 5, 4,3...
我的朋友们
我是亚特兰蒂斯探险队的Rodney McKay博士
My friends. I am Doctor Rodney McKay
of the Atlantis expedition,
鉴于我们同幽灵的英勇无畏的斗争
and as the facts of
our heroic struggle against the Wraith
以及你们已经知道的我们的阵亡
在这里我想告诉你们一些最终的想法
and our untimely demise are already known to you,
in that light I'd like to pass along some final thoughts.
我在天体物理学领域所受到的良好教育
以及我所得到的第一手的经验
Now my extensive educational training and
first hand experience in the field of astrophysics,
让我产生了一个独到的想法
关于地球, 或者是其他类似行星
has given me a unique perspective that few on Earth or
on any other planet for that matter, can match.
现在我想花一些时间
把这个想法传递给你们
I'd like to take a few moments now
to pass along that perspective to you.
我将从对某个主题的一些观察开始
它对我来说, 既亲近又亲切
I'll begin with a few observations on a subject
that is both near and dear to my heart.
领导才能...
Leadership...
Markham先生 Markham太太
Mr and Mrs Markham,
我是Elizabeth Weir博士
my name is Dr Elizabeth Weir
你们的儿子是我的探险队中的一员
and your son was a member of my expedition team.
非常抱歉, 我不得不告诉你们
他在自己的岗位上不幸殉职
It is with a deep regret that I have to inform you
that he was killed in the line of duty,
就在几天以前
just a few days ago.
他在保卫其他人的时候阵亡
He died in the defence of others
他的牺牲拯救了我们很多人
and his sacrifice may have saved many.
她那敏锐的好奇心正是你们的女儿
在她作为探险队一名科学家的职位上
Her keen curiosity are just some of the qualities
that your daughter displayed during her duties
所展示出来的优秀品质之一
as a scientist on my team.
她以及她的一些同事
就在几个星期以前, 突然死亡
She and several of her colleagues,
died suddenly, just a few weeks ago.
我没有特权告诉你们她的死因
不过我可以告诉你们...
I am not at liberty to reveal
the cause of her death, but I can tell you...
在她在这里工作的那段时间
that during her time here,
Dumais博士是某件具有
深远意义事情的一部分
Dr Dumais was a part of something very profound.
她在这里的所见所感
是她从来都没有想到过的
She saw and lived things
she never would have dreamed of before.
你们应该为你们的儿子感到骄傲
他在保卫其他人的时候英勇的牺牲
You can be very proud of your son,
knowing that he died bravely while defending others.
我承认我并不是很了解他...
I confess that I didn't know him as I could have...
不过我知道他在队伍中很受人爱戴...
But I do know that he was well liked and
very well respected among his peers...
而且我还听到他经常提起他的家人
and I was told of how often he spoke of his family.
我真的希望能够告诉你们更多
I do wish I could tell you more.
我相信作为军属, 你们能够理解...
I'm sure you understand as a military family...
女士, 完了么?
Are you done ma'am?
请给我一些时间, 中尉
Just give me a moment please Lieutenant.
我一直忙于我的工作
I am keeping busy with my job.
我努力工作, 就跟其他人一样
以确保这次探险的成功
I work hard, like everyone else
to ensure the success of this expedition,
同时还要感谢我们科学团队的领队
and also to please the leader of our science team.
不, 不, 不, 不, 不
No, no, no, no, no.
首先是这个序列
This sequence first
然后是第二个代码
and then the secondary code.
除非你想把我们炸飞
就不用管这个顺序
Unless you're intentionally trying to blow us up.
In which case, excellent work.
他并不是总能记住我的名字,
He does not always remember my name,
但是与他一起工作, 我感觉非常非常愉快
but I have enjoyed working for him very much.
这是什么? 谁做的? 是你做的么?
What is this? Who made this? You made this?
他是一个非常受人尊敬的, 勇敢的人
He is a very honourable and brave man.
噢! 哎哟! OK, 抽筋, 抽筋, 抽筋!
哎哟! 哎哟! 哎哟!
Oh! Ow! OK, cramp, cramp, cramp! Ow! Ow! Ow!
直到现在, 只要他愿意,
我仍然愿意为他效劳
Until then, I will continue to serve at his pleasure.
在一个代数俱乐部中, 我吻了一个女孩
为这个我差点得了传染性单核细胞增多症
I almost caught mono, kissing a girl during algebra club.
为此我整整一个月没有去上学
那段日子我一直在想念着学校
I missed an entire month of school.
现在, 那个吻仍然记忆犹新
所以那还是值得的
Still, the kiss was something,
so it was probably worth it.
April Bingham
可爱的金发碧眼的女孩
April Bingham. Cute blonde.
上帝啊, 我喜欢金发碧眼的女孩
特别是... 留有短发的那种
God, I love blondes,
especially with the... the short hair.
Samantha Carter, 如果你在看的话
Samantha Carter, if you're watching,
心中的火炬还在燃烧
很不幸, 很快就要熄灭了
the torch is still burning.
Sadly, soon to be extinguished.
你知道, 你应该知道
我想你只是太...
You know, you should know. I think you are just so...
你很伟大 真的, 真的伟大
Well, you're great. Really, really great.
我要说你是与我共事过的最优秀的科学家
I would go so far to say you're the hottest scientist
I've ever worked with. In fact there's
事实上我无法在一晚上的时间内
找到我自己
probably not a night goes by I don't find myself, uh.
OK, Ford?
刚才的不要
让我们重新回到...
Let's lose that and let's get back to ...
...领导才能
... leadership.
谁将会看到这个?
Who will be watching this?
任何你发送给的人
Anyone you're sending it to.
家人, 朋友, 心爱的人
Family, friends, loved ones.
在亚特兰蒂斯会有人看到这个么?
Will anyone from Atlantis be viewing this?
没有, 这些消息是私人的
No. Messages are private.
你可以想多恶心就多恶心
You can get as mushy as you want.
这是一条给星际之门指挥官
Jack O'Neill将军的消息
Uh, this is a message for
General Jack O'Neill of Stargate Command.
我认为我有责任告诉您我所认为的
这个探险队的领导者在决策中所犯下的
严重的错误
I feel it is my duty to inform you of what
I consider to be serious errors in judgement
among the leaders of this expedition.
最值得一提的, Elizabeth Weir博士
Most notably, Dr Elizabeth Weir.
她鲁莽的行为将这次探险队的成员
一次又一次的暴露在极端危险之下
Her actions have repeatedly and recklessly exposed
the people of this expedition to extreme danger.
最终导致我们陷入如此悲惨的境地
Leading us directly to the grave situation
we currently find ourselves in.
好吧?
You know what?
不如我离开这里
让你独自录下自己的抱怨?
How about I leave the room and let
you record your whining in private.
很好!
Fine!
我一直在记录Weir博士值得争议的行为
现在我将为您详细阐述
I've been keeping a record of Dr Weir's questionable
activities, which I would like to detail for you now.
我从来不在意狗狗
I never cared for dogs.
太多的工作, 太多的需求, 太多的不可预知性
Too much work, too needy, too unpredictable.
我的意思是, 你打开一扇门
伴随着极小的声音, 它们就不见了
I mean, you leave one door open,
the tiniest little cracks, and they're gone.
你四处找它们, 到处贴传单, 但没有用
而且由于你的父亲拒绝购买许可证
You look for them, you put up fliers, it's no use.
And since your father refused to pay for a license,
动物收养所也没有办法跟踪它们
the animal shelter has no way of tracking them.
天知道在那个小家伙身上发生了什么
God knows what happened to that little guy.
现在来说说猫咪
这又是一个完全不同的故事
Now cats, now that's a whole different story.
猫们自给自足, 它们可以信耐
你摇动盒子它们就会跑过来
Cats are self sufficient, they're dependable,
you shake the box they come running.
有些人说这是由于食物, 不过我的猫...
Some people say it's the food, but my cat... See,
我真地相信他喜欢我的陪伴
I truly believe he enjoys my company.
在结束一天的工作, 回到家里的时候
看到一张熟悉的脸在那里等你
这是一件多么惬意的事情
There's something very comforting about coming
home from work at the end of the day and having
a familiar face waiting for you, you know?
我扯远了, 说到哪了
对了
Still, I digress. Where was I. Right,
领导才能!
leadership!
在这里!
Over here!
没事, 我是朋友!
It's alright, I'm a friend!
请快一点! 这边!
Please, hurry! This way!
赶快! 这边
Hurry! This way.
你们还剩下多少人?
How many of you remain?
我不知道, 到处都是幽灵
I don't know, the Wraith are everywhere.
来, 喝这个, 这是水
Here, drink this. It is water.
Oren, 你看到他了么?
Oren, have you seen him?
自从幽灵到来之后就没有看到
谢谢你
Not since before the Wraith arrived. Thank you.
我们必须走了, 幽灵会找到我们的
We must go now, the Wraith will find us.
不, 它们找不到的
No they will not.
我们的飞船有一个防护罩
它们是看不见我们的
Our ship has a shield which makes it invisible to them.
你们在这里很安全
You are safe here.
休息一下, 我们马上就可以离开了
Just rest, we will leave soon.
最后, 我要对探险队每个成员的家人说
Finally I would like say something
to the families of every member of this expedition.
我真希望我能够告诉你们更多
你们所爱的人正在做的事情
I wish I could tell you more
about what your loved ones are doing,
某一天, 我希望你们能够发现
and some day I hope you find out,
因为你们会感到惊奇
because you will be amazed.
我要告诉你们我为他们当中的
每一个都感到无比的自豪
But I will tell you that I could not be
more proud of each and every one of them.
他们的英勇无畏让我震惊
Their heroism has amazed me.
他们的足智多谋让我感到惊奇
Their resourcefulness has staggered me.
Rodney 启动!
Rodney go!
正在启动!
Going!
现在!
Now!
我们面对的是非常可怕的敌人
以及一个无法预知的未来
We face a terrible enemy, and an uncertain future.
如果再没有我们的音信
But if we are never heard from again,
请确信你们所爱的人并不是孤独的
know that your loved ones
did not face that uncertainty alone.
我们会共同面对未来
We are facing our future together.
少校!
Major!
那里实在是太恶心了
It's pretty ugly out there.
这是Oren的家人?
Is this Oren's family?
不是
No.
在洗劫是之后
他们就再也没有看到过Oren
They have not seen Oren since the culling began.
这个村庄已经被洗劫一空了
The village is pretty much wiped out.
星际之门刚刚关上
The gate just shut off.
在幽灵可能对星际之门做点什么之前
我们应该尽快拨号离开这里
We should be able to dial up and get out of here
before the Wraith can do anything about it.
求你了, 少校, 再给Oren 一些时间吧
Please Major, give Oren more time.
如果他能够过来, 他现在已经到了
If he was able to get here, he would be here by now.
我们马上准备回去
We've gotta get back.
那就走吧
Then go.
我会留在这里找他, 直到天亮
你可以晚点再来接我
I will stay and search until day light,
you can return for me later.
我不能这样做
I can't do that.
我把Oren当作自己的家人, 少校
我很遗憾你无法理解...
I consider Oren as family Major,
I am sorry if you cannot understand without...
我理解, Teyla
不过我并不是试图...
I understand it Teyla,
but that's not the point I am trying to...
不管你愿不愿意, 我会留下来
With or without you, I am staying.
你会送命的
You won't make it.
那么我请求你也留下, 就一会儿
Then I ask that you stay as well,
just a little longer.
允许某些好一点的事情发生
Allow something good to come of this.
好吧, 我们再给他一点时间
Alright, we'll give him a little more time.
我知道你很为我担心, 妈妈
I know you worry about me Mum,
不过每次挑战到来的时候
我们都可以找到解决的办法
but somehow we've found a way
to arise to each challenge,
所以不用担心我的安全
so I wouldn't fret about my safety.
这里的人们, 来自数十个国家,
大家都心系在一起
It's the people here, from dozens of countries,
all connected by a single bond.
我们代表着地球上的人民
We represent the people of Earth,
只要有事情发生
我发现我们地球人
and if there's one thing
I've discovered about we Earthlings,
就会紧紧的团结在一起
我不会奇怪如果我带回...
we're a scrappy bunch.
I wouldn't be surprised if I bring back...
先生, 你不能说"地球人"
Doc, you can't say Earthlings.
你的妈妈没有足够的安全许可
Your Mother doesn't have enough security clearance.
她知道我来自地球, 这不是什么该死的秘密
She knows I'm from Earth son, it's not a bloody secret.
哦, 对
Oh, right.
对不起妈妈... 不管怎样
Sorry mum... anyhow.
授权使用囚犯来测试一种实验药品
Authorized using a prisoner
to test an experimental drug,
这显然违反了日内瓦协约
in clear violation of the Geneva convention.
授权降下星际之门防护盾
Authorized lowering the Stargate shield
当准备进入的人的身份
受到明显质疑的时候
when the authenticity of
incoming travellers was clearly in question.
还有一处风景
我在临死前没有能够看到
That's another sight I'll die without having seen.
如果你像我一样旅行了这么远
你会发现想念尼亚加拉瀑布
也不是什么大不了的事情
See, to be fair - when you've travelled
as much as I've travelled, you'd think that
missing Niagra Falls would be no big deal.
不过你知道么? 这种思念不停的折磨你
But you know what? It gnaws at you.
还有很多电影我都想看
不过我现在看不成了
Alot of movies I wish I'd seen, that I won't see now.
从来没有看过Grease, 既便是
我在还是一个孩子的时候就已经有了
一个Olivia Newton John的纪念品
Never saw Grease even though I had a thing
for Olivia Newton John when I was a kid.
我一直都想看Ghandi,
我只看了《第六感》的前半部分
一直想知道它是怎样收尾的
I always wanted to see Ghandi, only saw the first half
of the Sixth Sense, always wondered how that ended.
我的妹妹...
My sister...
Ford, 如果你把其它部分剪掉了
一定要把这部分留下, 好么?
Ford if you cut everything else,
just keep this part okay?
Jenny, 我是你的哥哥Rodney. 很显然
Jenny, it's your brother Rodney. Obviously.
我想说, 嗯...
I wanna say, umm...
我想说些什么
I wanna say something.
家人很重要
Family is important.
我意识到这一点是因为, 这里的人们
在某种程度上, 在心理上充当了家人的地位
I've come to realize that because the people here
have become a sort of surrogate family to me.
现在我知道你在想些什么
我从来不会去鼓吹那种情感, 不过...
Now I know what you're thinking, I've never been
the poster child for that kind of sentiment but...
当某个人即将面临死亡的时候
他看到的事物也更加透彻
when one's contemplating their own demise,
one sees things more clearly.
我真心地祝你好, 你知道
I really do wish you the best, you know.
我很抱歉我们无法更加亲近
And I'm sorry we weren't closer.
也许, ...
Perhaps, ...
如果我有机会度过这次难关
也许某一天我们就可以
if by chance I make it out of this,
perhaps one day we can be.
我也很想这样
And I would like that.
现在, 如果还有时间, 我想回到
领导能力这个主题上来
Now, if there's time, I'd like to go
back to the subject of leadership.
有人过来了
Someone's coming.
Oren!
这个家庭到底有多大?
How big is his family?
他们在路上一定碰到了其他人
They must have met up with others along the way.
这会是一个问题
That's gonna be a problem.
我无法想象你们还在这里
I didn't think you'd still be here.
我们不会丢下你的
We would not have gone without you.
我们发现其他人正在路上
还有更多人在更后面
We found others on the way,
and even more further behind.
还有多少人?
How many more?
十二个, 可能更多
Twelve, perhaps more.
这里
In here,
这边! 快点!
this way! Quickly!
等, 等, 等, 等, 等一下!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
好了, 我们会尽可能多的多带些人!
Alright, we'll fit as many people as we can!
快点, 来吧!
Hurry, come on!
一直向前! 一直向前!
Straight ahead! Straight ahead!
赶快!
Hurry!
没事的
It's alright.
我们的客人已经安置好了么?
Are our guests comfortably settled in?
是的
Yes.
很好
Good.
告诉我
So tell me,
到底有多糟糕?
how bad is it?
很糟糕
Bad.
每艘母船就像是一艘航空母舰
Each hive ship acts like a carrier group with
大舰以及数以百计的小飞船守卫在周围
cruisers and hundreds of darts escorting it.
Groden现在正在下载探测器上的读数
Groden's downloading the sensor readings right now.
我从没有看到过一次洗劫带走了这么多人
I've never witnessed a culling that took so many.
我们救出了一些人, 这还是值得肯定的
We saved a few, that's worth something.
Rodney, 我们准备好发送消息了么?
Rodney, are we ready to send our message?
随时都可以
When you are.
OK
OK.
Ford中尉刚刚完成为每个探险队成员
记录个人消息的工作
Lieutenant Ford is just finishing recording
personal messages from all the team members,
如果你愿意?
if you'd like?
我很好
I'm good.
好吧
Okay.
在我个人的一点简短的说明之后
Well along with a short note of my own,
我还顺便为我们失去的人的家人
录上了一些话
I took the liberty of recording messages
for the families of the people we've lost.
这是个好主意
That's a good idea.
不过还有一个特别的人
But there's one in particular,
我想也许应该由你自己来完成
I thought maybe you'd might like to do for yourself.
OK, 只要你准备好了, 长官
随时可以开始
Okay, whenever you're ready Sir. Go ahead.
我不知道Sumner上校的家人
是否还活着
I'm not sure if Colonel Sumner's
parents are still alive.
我甚至不知道他是否还留有一个家庭
我们大家都不知道
I'm not even sure he has
a family back there, not all of us do.
不过如果他确实有一个家庭
But if he does have a family,
他们应该知道他带着 ...
they should know that he died with ...
荣耀和勇气在完成他的任务的时候牺牲了
honour and courage in the perfomance of his duty.
他担负着领导的重担
而且他做得很出色
He carried the burden of a leader,
and he carried it well.
我没有机会更深入的了解他, 不过 ...
I didn't get the chance to know him well, but ...
我所知道的是
I know this,
考虑到他作为男人的品格
以及我们即将面对的敌人
considering the type of man
he was and what we're up against,
我希望他仍然在这里
yeah I wish he was still here.
我无时无刻不在想你Simon
Not a day goes by that I don't think of you Simon.
实在是有太多的事情想跟你说
There's so much I want to tell you
以及跟你分享
and share with you.
不过我不能
But I can't.
我知道这不公平
I know this is unfair,
那么多东西你都不知道
so much you don't know,
但你却要在生活中支持我
and putting your life on hold for me.
所以不要这样了
So don't,
我要你做的就是照顾好自己
all I ask is that you take care of yourself.
不管你在哪里
And know that wherever you are,
我的心会一直同你在一起
my heart is looking after you.
照顾好你自己
So take care of yourself,
多睡眠
lots of sleep
记住每天散步
and remember your daily walks,
坚持按你的药方服药
and keep up with your prescription.
就是这些
Well that's about it,
现在我要说再见了
I'll say goodbye now.
妈妈
And mum,
我真的很爱你
I do love you.
再见, 爷爷, 奶奶 - 我想你们!
Bye Grandma, Grandpa - I miss you!
再见, 弟弟!
Goodbye bro!
再见
Goodbye.
再见, Simon
Goodbye Simon.
再见
Goodbye.
我们收到了计划外的连接!
We have unscheduled offworld activation!
接收传输
Receiving transmission.
来自哪里?
Who's it from?
亚特兰蒂斯
Atlantis.